

PROFILE

Astute and highly analytical associate finance manager bringing strengths in handling work independently and solving problems without oversight. Highly regarded for ability to quickly learn new processes and deliver comprehensive reports while exceeding stringent expectations. Experienced in financial management, financial reporting and analysis, accounts payable and payroll.

CONTACT

PHONE: 618-867-2741

EMAIL: stefanietichacek@gmail.com

SKILLS

Budget Preparation
Financial Analysis
Financial Reporting
Account Reconciliation
Microsoft Office Suite
Microsoft Great Plains
Concur Invoice and Expense

STEFANIE TICHACEK

Associate Manager, Finance

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Manager, Finance

The Gideons International

Jul 2021 - present

- Managed budget procedures, including preparation of annual budget and monthly monitoring of departmental expenditures
- Prepared and analyzed monthly financial statements
- Monitored employee use of company credit cards and enforced compliance with travel and expense policies
- Supervised team member task lists to ensure timely month end close
- Served as internal administrator for financial and banking systems

Financial Analyst

The Gideons International Sept 2017 – July 2021

- Prepared organizational financial analysis and presented findings to Executive Leadership monthly
- Reconciled accounts monthly, including assets and bank and investment statements
- Maintained accurate accounting of investment portfolio for Finance Committee
- Managed and trained new users on financial systems
- Monitored daily cash position and tracked inflows/outflows from various sources

Accounts Payable Specialist

The Gideons International June 2017 – Sept 2017

- Processed all vendor payables during transition of systems
- Prepared monthly journal entries
- Assisted in annual audit

Office Executive

Spears Animal Hospital Dec 2015 – May 2017

- Compiled and analyzed monthly, quarterly, and yearly production reports
- Created monthly profit vs. expense summaries
- Managed accounts payable/receivable

EDUCATION

McKendree University

Aug 2012 - Dec 2015

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics (Finance – Actuary Track), Minor in Finance Summa Cum Laude, GPA: 4.0/4.0

ACTUARIAL EXAMS

Exam FM/2 - Dec 2016 Exam P/1 - May 2016